Saul Newbury – Front-End Web-Developer

Personal Statement

I am a highly motivated front-end web-developer, currently working to deepen my knowledge of JS and become proficient with React, whilst familiarising myself with Express and MongoDB; paving a way to becoming useful across the stack, whilst building upon previous experience working with HTML and CSS (in a Wordpress environment).

I am excited for the opportunity to apply and further hone my expanding knowledge within a professional setting, complimentary to my forging a career as a web-developer.

I will bring tenacity and enthusiasm to your team, with an eye for detail and appetite for learning! I'd love the opportunity to chat further, please get in touch to explore whether we'd be a good fit for each other.

Technical Skills

Css

Html

JavaScript

React

Express

MongoDB

Working with RESTful APIs

Transferable Skills

As private guitar tutor and musician:

Marketing and promotion
Planning and time management
Clear and affective communication
Attention to detail
Strong resource investigator

Employment History

2019 – now Graphic design and web-development

Distant Voice

Sep – Oct 2018 Graphic design and web-development

Copyology

June – Aug (2018) Sole designer/creator of S4M's Fusio Sales Deck

S4M

2011 – 2018 Self-promotion, branding and website design

Private guitar tutor and musician

Sept – Dec (2013) Designer Programmer and Editor

Elemental Practice LLP

Telefonica's Campus Party 2013, O2 arena

Aug 2010 – Oct 2013 Content writer and designer for slideshow

presentations

Applaud Entertainment

Education

2007 – 2009 BA Creative Sound Design for New Media

Academy of Contemporary Music

2006 – 2007 Music Production Higher Diploma

Academy of Contemporary Music

Hobbies & interests

In my spare time, I love building little JS apps that improve my coding ability. And whilst not at the computer, I love playing guitar and crafting songs, or getting out in nature, walking and cycling.